Guide to the William Benton Papers 1839-1973
University of Chicago Library
- Series II: Speech Files
  Djilas, Milovan, "Storm in Eastern Europe," New Leader, 11/19/56; #272
  Dodd, Tom, Benton's comments on Dodd's announcement of candidacy, 9/5/57; #15
  Dodd, Benton speech, "Tom Dodd's Availability as Candidate for Senatorial Nomination," no text, 7/7/56; #64
  Dodd, Benton speech, question-and-answer period with Benton and Bowles, Fairfield County Federation of Women's Clubs, no text, 5/20/58; #396
  Dodd, Benton speech, with Benton and Bowles, "Republican Curtailment of Urban Renewal Funds," Fairfield County Federation of Women's Clubs, 5/19/58; #396
  Donnelly, Raymond L., endorsement of Benton for Senator, undated; #382
  Douglas, Paul, In the Fullness of Time, 1971; #2298
  Douglas, radio, "Economy through Government Reorganization," 4/10/52; #881
  Douglas, "Government Reorganization"; #928
  Dulles, Allen, Russell Baker article, "The Other Mr. Dulles; Of the CIA," New York Times Magazine, 3/16/58; #266
  Dulles, speech, "Soviet Challenge; Science and Technology," Yale Conference, 2/3-4/58; #152K
  Dulles, television, "Democratic Platform Discussed," 8/23/64; #1891
  Dulles, Benton's commentary on Penn Kimball memo analyzing Convention and Senatorial nomination, 6/58; #1169
  Education, awarding of honorary LID from Bard College, 6/16/51; #731
  Education, awarding of honorary LID from Bard College, photos, 6/16/51; #731A, #1477, #1483
  Education, awarding of honorary LID from Bard College, Carleton, 6/61; #1808
  Education, awarding of honorary LID from Bard College, Dartmouth, photo, 6/68; #2193
  Education, awarding of honorary LID from Bard College, Knox College, photo, 6/6/60; #1763
  Education, awarding of honorary LID from Bard College, Montana State College, 6/16/57; #96
  Education, awarding of honorary LID from Bard College, Montana State College, photo, 6/10/57; #1540
  Education, awarding of honorary LID from Bard College, Notre Dame, 6/68; #2189
  Education, awarding of honorary LID from Bard College, University of Louisville, 6/48; #1493
  Education, awarding of honorary LID from Bard College, University of Montana, 6/10/57; #1429
  Education, Benton article, "Television; Trivia or Trivium? Is It a Choice?," Academy Magazine, 12/51; #388
  Education, Benton article, "How Can Radio Educate?," Know, 10/41; #79
  Education, Benton article, "Why Do United States Schools Fail to Create Scientists?," New York Post, 10/24/57; #288
  Education, Benton article, "Biggest Reward; A Tribute to Education," New York Times, 5/21/38; #466
  Education, Benton article, "United States Education and the Liberal Arts," Yale Political Union, Summer 1962; #1809
  Education, Lester David, "Are You Fed Up with TV Trivia?," 4/60; #1380
  Education, Barbara Kerr, "William Benton's Role in Education," 5/14/57; #1177
  Education, Ethel Beckwith, "TV as a Teacher; Quotations of William Benton," Bridgeport Sunday Herald Magazine, 10/18/59; #1292
  Education, book, The Teachers and the Taught in the U.S.S.R., 1966; #2080
  Education, book, H. G. Rickover, Education and Freedom, 1960; #2088
  Education, book, Edward M. Tuttle, Education by Will Versus Education by Order; #876
  Education, book, Edward M. Tuttle, School Board Leadership in America; #1214
  Education, Benton review of Arthur Trace, Jr., What Ivan Knows that Johnny Doesn't, 11/12/61; #1826
  Education, Benton letter, to editor, foreign aid and federal support to education for training scientists, New York Times, 5/31/56; #675
  Education, Benton letter, to editor, suggesting a council of educational advisors, New York Times Magazine, 3/30/62; #1862
  Education, Benton letter, to Eisenhower, television quiz scandal and need for citizen's advisory commission, 11/18/59; #1299
  Education, Benton letter, #2, 11/21/59; #1299A
  Education, Benton letter, #3, 11/30/59; #1299B
  Education, Benton letter, to Sigurd Larmon, television quiz scandal and the need for citizen's advisory committee, 12/1/59; #1299C
  Education, Benton letter, to Glen Lloyd, appraisal of University of Chicago, 11/20/59; #1362
  Education, Benton letter, to Charles Percy, television quiz scandal and the need for citizen's advisory committee, 12/2/59; #1299D
  Education, Warren Preece manuscript, Education in China, 1960; #1764
  Education, photo, Institute for International Education, 1969; #2303
  Education, photo, Open University, 5/16/72; #2287
  Education, radio, "Is Our Educational System Failing the Individual?," 2/6/58; #152U
  Education, radio, 4/11/60; #1605
  Education, radio, 4/5/61; #1394
  Education, speech, "Education; Liberal Arts versus Business Schools," 2/15/61; #1765A
  Education, speech, "Educational Radio Broadcasting," Commonwealth Edison, 3/14/38; #862
  Education, speech, "Television; Subscriptional and Educational," Dinner Club, no text, 4/13/59; #1287
  Education, speech, "Television; How Can the Public Interest Best Be Served?," Institute for Education by Radio and Television, 5/3/52; #501
  Education, speech, "Television," Overseas Press Club, 2/13/64; #1937
  Education, speech, "Radio Broadcasting; Educational and Otherwise," Parents' Association, 10/24/39; #865
  Education, speech, "Tribute to William Carr," National Education Association, 6/19/67; #2154
  Education, speech, "Private School in a Changing World," Taft School alumni, 12/12/41; #1301
  Education, speech, "Education; Expansion of University of Connecticut," Tolland County Democratic Association Picnic, no text, 8/18/57; #54
  Education, speech, "Improving Education in Our Schools," United Parents' Association, 1/13/62; #1815
  Education, summary of efforts on behalf of education; #325
  Education, television, shortage of educational facilities, 11/6/59; #1364
  Education, testimonial, Institute for International Education, 4/15/70; #2252
  Education, testimony, proposal for a citizens' board on broadcasting, Carnegie Commission on Educational Television, 4/15/66; #2114
  Education, in Britain, "English Education through the Looking-Glass; A Comparative Journey into American High Schools," report financed by Benton Foundation, 4/30/58; #414
  Eisenhower, Dwight D., letters to Benton, television quiz scandals and need for Citizen's Advisory Committee, 11/59; #1299-1299B
  Eisenhower, letter to Nickolai Bulganin, atomic weapons, summit meeting, and strengthening the U. N., 2/18/58; #255
  Eisenhower, photo, testifying in favor of Smith-Mundt bill, 5/20/47; #1488
  Eisenhower, statement, two speeches, "Science and Security" and "Future Security," 11/16/57; #187
  Eisenhower, Benton testimonial, Information Program, 6/6/47; #1202
  Eisenhower, Exchange Fellowships, Inc., Benton's appointment to Board of Trustees, 11/17/52; #1184
  Eisenhower, Exchange Fellowships, Board of Trustees pay tribute to President on his birthday, 10/14/53; #1470
  Election laws, article, Ann Ferebee, "Political Campaigns," Commonweal, unpublished, ca. 1958; #1038
  Election laws, guide book, Summary of Federal and State Laws Regulating the Nomination and Election of United States Senators, 1952; #1028
  Election laws, guide book, Federal Corrupt Practices and Political Activities Laws; #1027
  Election laws, Benton letter to Alexander Holmes, abolishing the vice presidency, Connecticut newspapers; #1927
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, announcement, "William Benton Returns as Chairman of the Board," 10/9/47; #806
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, announcement, "Hubert Humphrey Joins EB Board of Directors," 1/9/69; #2217
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, announcement, "Purchase of Merriam Webster Co.," 9/11/64; #2008
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, announcement, "Purchase of the Praeger Publishers," 4/22/66; #2118
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, announcement, "William Benton Announces Gifts of EB Collection of American Paintings to American Schools," 4/16/50; #893
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, announcement, "Encyclopaedia Britannica Collection of Art to Be Shown in Sacramento," 3/1/48; #1179
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Robert Alden, "Benton Sees Vast Publishing Gains," New York Times, 1/14/60; #1392
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, John Benton, "First Sales Experience," EB News, 9/1/59; #1246
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "In Memoriam; Adlai E. Stevenson," Book of the Year, 1966; #2110
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," ibid., 1966; #2110
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," ibid., 1967; #2138
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," ibid., 1968; #2167
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," ibid., 1969; #2213
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," ibid., 1970; #2244
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," ibid., 1971; #2260
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," ibid., 1972; #2290
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," ibid., 1973; #2313
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "The Teachers and the Taught in the U.S.S.R.," ibid., 1965; #2000
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Voice of the Kremlin," ibid., 1956; #31
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Voice of Latin America," ibid., 1961; #1740
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," Compton's, 1971; #2261
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," ibid., 1972; #2311
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," ibid., 1973; #2289
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Russian Trip," EB News, 1/56; #105
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Reginald Marsh," Know, Summer 1967; #113A
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Meet John Y. Brown II," ibid., 1972-1973; #2293
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," EB Roundtable, 1/73; #2308
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," ibid., 1972; #2309
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Shaping Our Lives Through Science and Technology," ibid., 1972; #2280
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Thank God for Salesmen," Salesman's Opportunity, 1968; #2184
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "1973; The Year of the Salesman," ibid., 2/73; #2320
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Mikoyan vs. Britannica," Saturday Review, 10/27/62; #1312
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Publisher's Message," Yearbook of Science and the Future, 10/69; #2229
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Shaping Our Lives Through Science and Technology," ibid., 1968; #2192
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Shaping Our Lives Through Science and Technology," ibid., 1970; #2255
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Shaping Our Lives Through Science and Technology," ibid., 1972; #2265
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William Benton, "Shaping Our Lives Through Science and Technology," ibid., 1973; #2288
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Clay Cole, "How the Britannica Sells One Out of Three," Sales Management, 6/3/60; #1615
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Harvey Einbinder, "Straight Look at the Encyclopaedia Britannica," Columbia University Forum, Winter 1960; #1398
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Harvey Einbinder, "The Britannica; An American Critique of the Encyclopedia Business," Encounter, 1961; #1398B
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Harvey Einbinder, letters to editor, Hutchins's refutation and Einbinder's response, Columbia University Forum, Spring 1960; #1398A
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Harvey Einbinder, "Our Imperfect Encyclopedias," Progressive, 3/61; #1398B
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Harvey Einbinder, The Myth of the Britannica, 1964; #1940
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Bruce Felknor, "William Benton; Looking Back," Know, Fall 1972/Winter 1973; #2293A
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Paul Hoffman and others, "World Without Want," ibid., 1962; #1859
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Arthur Bartlett, "Bill Benton; Idea Man on the Run," Coronet, 9/48; #149
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Ray Josephs, "The Great EB," Christian Science Monitor, 6/58; #292C
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Dorothea Kahn, "Encyclopaedia Britannica; A Long Time Newspaper," Christian Science Monitor, 7/10/43; #1010
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Allan Keller, "Filed But Never Forgotten," World Telegram and Sun, 2/10/62; #1855
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Michael Lazare, "The Marvelous Encyclopedia Business," Forbes, 2/15/65; #2048
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Arthur M. Louis, "The Friendly Britannica," The Nation, 3/1/65; #2051
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, William A. Lydgate, "Britannica," Reader's Digest, 6/42; #1584
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Kent MacDougall, "Facts for Sale," Wall Street Journal, 2/19/68; #2182
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Jessie Matson, "Britannica in Eighteenth-Century America," Metropolitan Museum of Art Library Bulletin, 6/43; #898
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Richard A. Smith, "Ceiling on Selling," Fortune, 8/58; #368
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Carl Spielvogel, "Advertising; Hard Sell No News to Benton," ibid., 5/25/58; #975
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, John Tebbel, "Two Hundred Years of Progress," Saturday Review, 2/10/68; #2183
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, John H. Thompson, "University of Chicago Aide's Action Saves Britannica Bonanza," Chicago Tribune, 10/8/72; #2321
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Walter Yust, "That's a Fact-Or Is It?," Catholic Library World, 3/57; #258
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, "Future Encyclopedias," 1964; #1986
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, "Bill Benton's Knowledge Empire," Fortune, 1/68; #2186
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, "Growth of EB," Fortune, 7/58; #368
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, "This Was the 'Athens of America,'" New Haven Register, 3/20/60; #1608
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, book, commemorating 200th anniversary, 1/69; #2211B
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, book, Franklyn H. Hooper, Story of the Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1939; #1071
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, book, Harcourt F. Kitchin, Moberly Bell and His Times, 1925; #1838
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, book, Herman Kogan, The Great EB, 4/58; #292
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, book, Joseph McCabe, Lies and Fallacies of the Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1947; #1928
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, book, Board of Editors of Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1962; #1303
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, book, Carl F. Stover, edited, The Technological Order, proceedings of EB Conference, 1963; #1334
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, booklet for Board of Editors; #1303
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, gift, Contemporary American Painting catalogs to U. S. missions abroad, 6/1/58; #476
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, gift, 5 sets as Christmas presents to Soviet Presidium members, 12/25/55; #112
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, gift, 5 sets to Israel Projects Program as Zionist Organization of America, 12/14/50; #507
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, gift, presentation to German newspapers, 7/19/48; #1352
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, gift, Rumanian Five Language Technical Lexicon, to reciprocate for 3 sets to Rumanian libraries, 8/26/60; #1771
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, gift, 50 sets to news agencies of Germany, 7/19/48; #1353
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, gift, 50 sets to German newspapers and DENA, 4/27/49; #791
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, editorial revisions, 1/4/63; #1319
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, John Benton letter to parents about EB sales experience, 8/27/62; #1246A
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, memo, transfer, 7/59; #292B
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, memo, General Robert E. Wood, "Monument for the World; Building of the Panama Canal," 11/63; #1333
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, photo, Great Books presentation, 4/52; #1434
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, photo, publication of The Great EB, 5/58; #1568
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, photo, Benton tribute, 5/24/49; #1511
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, photo, meeting of Board of Directors, 1957; #1529
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, photo, Canadian Medal presentation, 10/68; #2216
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, photo, First Edition replica, 10/68; #1497
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, photo, Kennedy Memorial Library, 3/3/65; #2055
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, photo, Adlai Stevenson at Geneva cocktail party, 7/8/65; #2089
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, photo, 3/60; #1182A
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, photo, reception by British Prime Minister and Guildhall dinner, 10/15/68; #2211A
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, photo, EB sales convention, 5/18/70; #2253
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, promotional literature, Benton, "Message to College Men," 1/59; #1182
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, radio, 2/21/64; #1943
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, radio, Benton's account of Russian trip, 7/22/62; #1305
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, radio, discussion of television quiz shows, payola, Latin American trip, and EB, 1/23/60; #1601
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, radio, 6/25-26/64; #1984
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, radio, forthcoming Russian trip and EB, 10/11/55; #980
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, radio, overseas broadcast, 190th anniversary of EB, 6/6/58; #1104
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, radio, Benton's views on business, 12/61; #1795
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, "Academy for Adults," 10/9/62; #1906
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, Compton Achievement Conference, 10/7/72; #2295
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, "Decade Ahead," 190th anniversary of publication of Encyclopaedia Britannica, 6/10/58; #511
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, dinner commemorating Benton's 25th anniversary as publisher, 2/1/68; #2179
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, Preble's retirement, 9/30/59; #1277
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, "UNESCO; The Dream Comes of Age,"" 10/11/67; #2163
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, EB international sales division meeting, 6/26/67; #2158
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, two short speeches in Scotland at reception honoring Britannica's 200th anniversary, 5/15/68; #2197
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, Encyclopaedia Britannica International Sales Conference, 10/13/68; #2212
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, Benton's response to Prime Minister's toast, 10/15/68; #2211
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, Harvard Business School Club, 6/1/65; #2065
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, introducing The Annals of America, 2/26/69; #2220
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, Wisconsin sales convention, 5/18/70; #2253
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, Magazine Writers Society, no text, 6/6/57; #97
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, presentation to President Johnson of books for 700 elementary schools, 12/14/67; #2174
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, Temac meeting, not delivered, 10/4/62; #1905
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, Young Executives in Sales Club, outline, 2/9/61; #1791
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, "In Memoriam; Robert Redfield," 11/18/58; #1035
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, speech, sales meeting for Encyclopaedia Britannica Canada, Ltd., 7/29/65; #2085
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Clifton Fadiman speech, conference of division managers, 2/3/65; #2050
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, Robert Preble speech, "Ethics in Selling," 4/13/59; #485
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, statement, physics film course, 2/16/57; #45
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, statement, sales training film, 12/59; #1381
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, statement, year-end statement, 12/59; #1382
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, statement, Geoffrey Crowther appointed to board of EB, Ltd., 4/12/56; #47
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, television, panel discussion of English language word usage, 6/22/59; #1213
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, tribute, Benton and the Great Books, 3/60; #1224A
  Encyclopaedia Britannica, tribute, "Tribute to William Benton and Encyclopaedia Britannica," Wisdom Magazine, 7/59; #1224
  Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, announcement, "Adlai Stevenson Accepts Chairmanship of Advisory Board," 4/10/57; #24
  Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, Benton, "Sound Movies for Sound Education," University of Chicago Magazine, 11/43; #771
  Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, Paul F. Healey, "They Make the Strangest Movies," Saturday Evening Post, 3/7/59; #1240
  Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, Robert Hutchins, "Founding of Company," University of Chicago Alumni Bulletin, 10/44; #778
  Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, Maurice Mitchell, "Communications," Britannica Book of the Year, 1958; #517
  Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, memo, Charles Benton, "Russian Trip," 9/64; #2042
  Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, memo, Milan Herzog, Russian trip, 9/64; #2043
  Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, photo, Adlai Stevenson accepts Advisory Board chairmanship, 4/57; #1537
  Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, script, "Bill Benton; Fighting Senator," 7/21/52; #1236
  Encyclopaedia Britannica Films, speech, "McCarthy's Lies in Regard to Communist Employees of Encyclopaedia Britannica Films," Waterbury Democrats, 10/29/52; #935
  Encyclopedia history, Richard McKeon manuscript, "History of Encyclopedias and the Functions of Encyclopedia," 1950; #466
  English language, "English Spoken Here, There, Everywhere," Think, 1/2/67; #2116C
  English language, "King's English; Taken for a Ride," This Week Magazine, 6/25/38; #896
  English language, Japan American Society, 10/69; #2241
  Evans, Luther H., "Almost Half the World's Adults Can't Read," New York Times Magazine, 3/16/58; #268
  Evans, Benton letter about Russian propaganda and distortions of history, 12/1/55; #131
  Explorer's Club, autographed tribute to Benton from several members, 1/7/39; #1534
  Marshall Field III: A Biography, Stephen Becker book, 5/64; #1907A
  Field, Benton interview with Becker, 10/17/62; #1907
  Fitzpatrick, Raymond J., appointed to staff for Benton Senatorial nomination, 1/2/58; #28
  Fitzpatrick, letter and Benton reply, "Benton Can Win," 1/15/58; #285A
  Fitzpatrick, memo, "Senatorial Nomination; Convention Analysis," 6/58; #1072
  Fitzpatrick, memo, "Quick and Easy Reforms, or DeGaulle Showed the Way," drafts, 7/59; #1089
  Flanders, Ralph E., Senator from Vermont, 1961; #2005
  Flanders, letter to Arthur Watkins, McCarthy's refusal to answer charges in Hennings-Hayden-Hendrickson Report of January 1953, 8/30/54; #1007
  Flying Clipper, Jack Zaiman, "Needle's Eye; Cheapest Vacation," Hartford Courant, 9/59; #1290
  Flying Clipper, reunion party monologue, Adlai Stevenson, 10/24/59; #1293
  Flying Clipper, reunion party monologue, Marietta Tree, 10/24/59; #1286
  Flying Clipper, reunion party monologue, Suzette Zurcher, 10/24/59; #1295
  Flying Clipper, photo, Venice cruise, 6/61; #1001
  Flying Clipper, photo, "Visit to Leningrad," 8/21/60; #1766
  Foreign policy, announcement of Benton's membership in Committee for a United Europe, 7/3/53; #21
  Foreign policy, appointment to Democratic Advisory Committee on Foreign Policy, 9/26/57; #56
  Foreign policy, Benton article, "Education and American Foreign Policy"; #2133
  Foreign policy, Award for Distinguished Contribution to International Relations, New York Federation of Women's Clubs, 10/27/50; #454A
  Foreign policy, debate, University of Minnesota, 10/22/56; #61
  Foreign policy, debate, World Affairs Council, 10/15/56; #63
  Foreign policy, Benton letter, to Acheson, budget needs of Information Program, 5/16/46; #690A
  Foreign policy, Benton letter, and Warren Austin reply, Marshall Plan of Ideas, 10/50; #151H
  Foreign policy, Benton letter, to editor, summit conference for Middle East and expanded Information Program, New York Times, 8/10/58; #759
  Foreign policy, Benton letter, to editor, training scientists and foreign aid and federal support for education, ibid., 5/31/56; #675
  Foreign policy, Benton letter, to Kenneth McKellar, budget needs for Voice of America, 9/2/50; #523
  Foreign policy, Benton letter, to Kenneth McKellar, fund slash for Voice of America, 4/17/51; #1039
  Foreign policy, Benton letter, to Robert McLean, press disputes and the State Department, 1/17/46; #1155
  Foreign policy, Benton letter, to Sabath and members of Rules Committee, grain to India, 4/20/51; #467